If you put a lie detector test on me,
the truth is, I think the days
of running a business using a laptop,
your phone, camera, are limited.
And I genuinely believe the only way for
most people to survive is to create a
personal brand. And very quickly,
what that means is,
there needs to be a person
associated to the business.
Social media was built for people.
You might love your local shop,
Woolworths or Tesco or whatever, but you
don't see it on social media and go, "Wow,
can't wait to follow Tesco." You might
love Michelin tires, but you're not like,
"Oh, going to follow Michelin." You build
connections with people. You go, "Wow,
that person's really funny.
I love that comedian.
I'm following him." Believe it or not,
humans are really good
at building connections with other humans.
The reason Nutonic is doing so well
is yes, the product is amazing,
but there are
other amazing products in the market doing
terribly because they are not connected
to personal brands.
For some of you watching this,
you might have watched me for
hours, even days of content.
You might listen to my podcast for silly
amounts of
time.
So when I tell you about the product
and say it's good and the money-back
guarantee,
you are trusting the personal brand.
The only reason that any of you will even
like me is because of that raw duration
of time that you spend content in front of
me.
Now, the majority of you,
the biggest problem you have is content.
It's not good enough.
You don't put enough out.
But what you don't realize
is both of these fix each other.
What I mean by that is this.
If you put out more content,
you'd get better at
content. But also,
if you're better at content,
you put out more content.
You're in this strange beta region paradox
where you're not quite
sure your way out,
and the advice I would give you
is to pump more content.
Now, I'm yet to see anyone truly crush
or build a
personal brand with an iPhone.
If it's all you have, that's okay.
But there's some issues I have with it,
and it's not actually the camera quality.
It's that I would prefer
that you disconnected the purpose of that
because this should be for emails,
FaceTiming your parents, scrolling on
Insta before bed,
taking pictures of your dog,
and this should be
for building your personal brand.
Now, this is the DJI Pocket Osmo 3,
and I recommend it to a lot of content
creators. Now,
it's not even the versatility of this.
It's not the fact it's got a gimbal.
It's a little bit to do with that.
I just want a device
that the only purpose it has in your life
is for
building a personal brand.
I'm going to use this very thing here with
a landscape
or portrait,
and it's to communicate with people
that are going to be perfect
clients for me. Every single day,
this device,
and it could be another camera,
whatever. I'm going to talk to it.
I'm going to use good hooks
and good setups and
good payoffs,
and I'm going to help people build
and accrue large amounts of time
in front of me watching content.
It's one of the reasons I created
Short-Form
Content Mastery,
which there'll be a link to in the
description.
It's only $99, and it can really help you.
And one of the biggest things I want from
this is intention.
When I turn this on, it's go time. Now,
is this the best camera? No.
That is the best camera.
But I got to a million followers without a
studio,
without my own space. And the truth is,
for the majority of you, this is overkill.
That is a Sony FX3. The microphone
is out of shot.
That light and that camera
are perfectly paired.
The reason this room is dark is so
that we can control the light
and then the hair
light to the side.
I have a professional studio because I'm
three stages ahead
of you. You do not need this.
And to be honest, with the stage
that you're at, this
would be overkill. What you need
is hundreds of repetitions back to that.
And the thing is, in content,
social media platforms, whatever.
People seem to think it's the algorithm
that goes, "Okay, sir, you've posted
2,000 times.
We're going to show you to more people."
No,
it's not the algorithm doing this thing.
It's you.
I've created thousands of pieces of
content over a decade.
And my ability to produce organic content,
which this is.
There's no financial spend behind this
video.
Every single view on this video
is organic.
It's earned through the process of putting
out content.
And I'll be real with you as well.
The reason that my paid ads even do well
is because of the organic.
Think of it this way.
When I do a paid ad in front of someone,
they probably have seen the face before.
I've got billions of impressions online
through Instagram, Facebook, TikTok,
podcasts, whatever.
Even going on Piers Morgan,
Good Morning Britain.
All of those combined,
when someone sees an advert, go,
"I've seen that guy.
Oh, it's the fitness guy.
It's the guy from Facebook,"
or whatever it is.
Even to get good at paid ads,
you need that organic presence beforehand.
And for me,
there has to be a shift where this
is for personal, for fun.
This is for work. Even this room here,
I only use to produce content.
I don't hang out in here.
I don't even enter this building unless
I'm coming here
to produce content.
You may have noticed the last six months
to 12
months just got incredibly difficult,
more difficult than ever to win over
business.
And it's because producing content has
become easier.
People can put scripts into Claude.
They can copy transcripts
and put it into AI.
The amount of tools
that people have means
that bad content creators are getting
better at the quickest rate ever.
And I'm not trying to promote a doomsday
narrative. I'm just saying that in one,
two, three years time, there are going to
be the people that pumped content at a
mass volume.
There's that Alex Hormozi story
that he stole from someone where get
someone to
make a perfect vase.
Get a group make the perfect vase,
but you get the other group
to make as many vases as possible.
In a year's time, the group
that did the volume
of vases probably make a better perfect
vase than the ones that just obsessed over
the perfect vase.
I need you to do 100 videos as quick as
possible of the
same five to 10 themes within your niche
and problems that people face.
Then two or three of them
are going to do way better than everything
else.
And you go back and you examine, you go,
"Hmm, why did they do better?" You double
down,
you make three more variations of those.
Before you know it, you've got a bucket,
you've got an outlier.
And then you might double into it more,
and then suddenly you're like, "Okay, I'm
onto something here.
I'm going to build a lead magnet from
those videos that
outperformed all the other things within
my ecosystem.
I'm going to chuck the lead magnet in
there. I'm going to get emails.
Then I'm going to build a product for
those people, and we're going to flesh it
out." Because imagine this. Imagine
if I said,
"There's only three years left to
social media. Would you work harder?"
If so, you need to start now.
If I said you only had three years to
maximize your time
building an online personal brand,
would you work harder? If so, yes.
Because I hope I'm wrong.
I really hope I'm wrong.
I hope that in three years time you go,
"James, it wasn't as bad as you said." But
if it is, it's worth getting ready anyway.
I remember seeing a story with those
really bad fires that happened in LA, in
California. And one guy saw the bushfires,
and he was going to prepare for the
worst.
And he ended up creating a sprinkler
system that connected to his swimming
pool. And a lot of people were like,
"This guy's mental.
It's never going to be that bad again.
What the hell are you doing?"
And then when the bushfires came,
he had a system.
He protected his house.
Better to have that and be ready
and never need it
than just sit back and go, "Oh,
that would never happen."
If you had three years,
would you work more? And is it really
that difficult to talk to this every day,
portrait once a week,
landscape to find an editor on Upwork to
edit
it for you if you haven't got the time?
Because this is how it is.
If you're broke,
you have the time to edit.
And if you're not broke
and you're too busy,
you have the money to offload some of
the editing to someone else.
If you don't believe me,
look at this YouTube channel.
Look at the cadence of uploads
that I'm putting out.
I'm putting a YouTube video out every
three days. Why?
Because I'm worried
that my ability to make money in my
niche may not be here in only a few years'
time.
If you don't believe what I say,
believe what I'm doing.
I am increasing the amount of output
content out there to get the amount of
leads I
can to close the amount of business,
help the amount of people before
potentially I
am made redundant.
And I already have a personal brand.
I am doing what I can to survive,
and I already have a personal
brand. Short Form Content Mastery,
link in description. It's $99.
It's like 70 quid.
Going to teach you all the things you need
to know about
creating short-form content so you can get
to work. And think of it.
If you get one client from the big uptick
in output that you're putting
out, it pays for it.
Your $99 purchase isn't going to change my
life.
But the reason I made this video is
that in two years' time,
you're going to see me
out and about, give me a fist bump and go,
"Mate, that video was exactly what I
needed."